Welcome everybody to the August 4th,
2026 finance committee meeting. Um just
a couple housekeeping items. If you
could please turn your phones to either
silent or off. Um and I think that's
all. Uh, Jen, if you could please read
the first item.
>> Number 11 G, preventative maintenance
contract between the City of Cheyenne
Fire Rescue Department and Striker
Corporation for a three-year maintenance
service contract for all city medical
devices.
>> Is there a staff report?
>> Uh, chair, council members, Deputy Chief
Roger Shy Fire Rescue. The service
agreement in front of you is to provide
maintenance for all of the cities and
fire departments EMS maintenance
equipment for AEDs and any life-saving
medical equipment. The contract is
$40,000 over three years. It's a
three-year service contract.
Thank you. Any questions for deputy
chief?
Hearing none comments from the public.
>> Mr. Miller, you can go ahead.
>> Uh, yes. Can you hear me?
>> We can hear you, sir.
All right.
Um, this is item number 11. Striker
Corporation three-year fire rescue
maintenance contract. Correct.
Um, I just uh Charles Miller for the
record. Uh,
I just wanted to comment on this. If our
primary operating reserves are liquid
enough to insulate private medical
device conglomerates like Striker with
three-year general fund maintenance
guarantees, they are liquid enough to
replace the toxic pipes poisoning our
children, fix the water, then protect
the corporate contracts. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Even though uh that comment
had nothing to do with this contract.
Any other public comment?
Are there comments from the committee?
Hearing none. All those in favor? Oh.
Oh. Can I have a motion, please?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $121,389.50
for a three-year period.
>> Second.
>> Moved by Councilman Crave, seconded by
Councilman Moody. Any other comments
from the committee? Uh, Mr. Chairman,
can we just get a correction that it's
not 50 cents, it's 60 cents. I must have
uh hit the wrong button.
>> Mr. Chairman, uh, my motion is for
121,38960.
>> Okay, great. That correction, that
correction is moved and seconded. Um,
any other comments from the committee at
this time?
Hearing none. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> That item's unanimous that and we'll
move forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 11H. Professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and AVIPC for Story Boulevard and Summit
Drive Construction Administration
Services.
>> Staff report.
>> Uh, sorry, it's me.
>> Okay. Go ahead, Mr. Cob chairman U and
members of the finance committee. Tom
Cobb, city engineer. I apologize. I'm
not there today. I am with my grandson.
So, we'll just say it's a good day.
>> Um, go ahead, sir. before you and for
your consideration. Um I is enclosed uh
a contract professional service
agreement between city of Cheyenne and
Avi Professional Corporation for
construction administrative services
associated with the story boulevard
summit drive project in accordance with
the procurement of professional services
for architects and engineers and land
surveyors. I selected AVI using
statements of qualifications currently
on file with my office. Uh the
purchasing of policy allows SOQ based
selection for engineering professional
services under 200,000 without a formal
RFP. Um provided firms are chosen from
the maintain SOQ list on my office. Um I
selected three SOQs and obviously I
selected AVI for two primary reasons.
their intimate understanding of the
design decisions, coordination
requirements and constraints finalized
in the approved construction plans
because they completed those plans and
the complexity of the project including
coordination with the county wat and
multiple utilities and adjacent drainage
and improvements on project. Um funding
for this modificate or this this
contract will be from the 2022 to 23 1%
optional sales tax fifth penny. The cost
not to exceed is a contract amount of
1963440
and it's consistent with the scope and
fee that they have they supplied me. I
respectfully request approval for their
professional services agreement. And
with that, I'll take any questions you
might have of me.
>> Thank you, Mr. Cobb. Questions for from
the committee for Mr. Cobb?
Hearing none comments from the public?
Mr. Miller, you can go ahead.
>> Go ahead, Mr. Miller.
>> Can you hear me?
>> I believe we can hear you always.
>> Um, Mr. Chairman, members of the finance
committee for the permanent
administrative record. My name is
Charles Miller. I'm testifying today to
place a formal constructive notice of
systemic arbitrage, fiduciary
misallocation, and conflict of interest
onto the official transcript regarding
item number 11H, the $196,3340
P professional services agreement with
AVIPC. I ask this committee to reject
this contract based on three severe
structural defects. First, the private
lobbyist subsidy. Th this agreement
commits nearly $200,000 of public funds
to AVIPC. Yet the public record is
clear. AVIPC and its principal Mark
Christensen act as the primary private
agents and lobbyists pushing to annex
and zone thousands of acres of rural
Cheyenne land to facilitate speculative
highdensity industrial data center
development.
>> Point of order has been called and
taken. Uh the fact that your allegation
is on annexations has nothing to do with
this contract.
>> I I object. I I believe I should be able
to speak my piece here. If you keep your
comments to this professional service
agreement and the project that is it is
considered on, I will allow you to
continue. And if not, then I won't.
>> Um, well, paying the developers chief
lobbying firm with public money to
administer the very
excuse me uh to
>> point of order has been called and point
of order is taken. Mr. Miller, I am
going to no longer allow your comments
on this item. Thank you, sir. Any other
comments from the public
hearing? None. Is there a motion from
the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman.
>> Oh,
>> go ahead, Mr. Speaker.
>> I move to approve an amount not to
exceed $196,3340.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
from the committee.
Hearing none. All those in favor of this
agreement, please signify by saying I.
I. I. Any opposed? That item passes
unanimously and we'll move forward. Next
item, please.
>> Number 12A, consideration of bid number
S-22-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Legacy Construction Group
for the Christensen Road Detention
Erosion Mitigation Project. Staff
report.
>> Good afternoon, chairman. Uh Tom Cobbs,
city engineer. Um before you and for
your consideration is the bid between
ourselves with Legacy Construction. I've
I've been with this item and asked for
postponement a couple of times. I now
would ask that you approve this contract
today um in the amount that is shown. Um
I do have a final meeting with the Union
Pacific Railroad this week. It should be
determined by Friday. Um and I will let
you all know on Monday. Um if if that
goes well, I would recommend final
approval, but I would like to move it
forward at this time.
>> Okay. Uh questions. Mr. Councilman
Moody. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Thank
you. Uh, thank you, Mr. Cob. That was
very helpful. Um, for the, uh, Monday
meeting, you said you're meeting with
Union Pacific this week. Um, would you
recommend this be pulled off consent
agenda so we can hear your comments and
so the public knows?
>> Chairman White through you to Council
Moody. Yes, sir. I would recommend that.
>> Thank you. Thank you. Any other
questions or comments from the committee
for Mr. Cobb?
Hearing none comments from the public.
Go ahead, Mr. Miller.
Can you hear me?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Um, okay. Uh, Mr. Chairman
uh Charles Miller for the permanent
record. Before I address the substance
of item 12A, let the record reflect that
during the discussion on item 11H, this
committee unlawfully cut my microphone.
I place this body on formal notice under
the Supreme Court's
>> Are you going to keep your comments 12A?
Sir, are you going to rehash the
previous item?
>> A public comment period is a
constitutionally protected limited
public forum muzzling a taxpayer for
making comparative arguments.
allocation of public funds is
unconstitutional.
>> Are you going to keep your comments to
12A? If not, if yes, I will uh let you
continue. If not, then we
>> just keep moving.
>> Well, first uh your docket indicates
that this current erosion mitigation
project is being funded by draining
unexpended cash from the 2012 and 2017
specific purpose option tax funds. Is
that correct?
I don't believe. Well, it shows that
that that specific tax fund is how we're
funding this particular project.
>> Okay. Well, let the math sink in. You
are funding a 2026 public works project
with voter approved tax overages that
have been sitting on your ledgers for up
to 14 years. Hoarding public capital for
over a decade while construction costs
and inflation comp compound represents a
total failure of administrative
execution. Why has this project sat idle
while the purchasing power of those
voter approved dollars degraded?
Um second, uh Christensen Road is the
primary transport transportation artery
directly serving the massive camp stool
and Highlands heavy industrial zones.
The massive grading, soil compaction,
and extensive impervious services
created by the rapid expansion of
private developer data center campuses
are the direct catalysts for the severe
hydraological runoff and erosion. this
project is forced to mitigate. Instead
of requiring these multi-billion dollar
developers to fully fund their own storm
water detention and localized erosion
control, you are draining decade old
public sales tax reserves to subsidize
their infrastructure footprint. This is
a textbook violation of the Wyoming
Constitution's anti-donation clause,
article 16, section 6, which strictly
prohibits the gifting of public credit
to private corporate enterprises. You
cannot claim the city lacks the funds to
replace toxic lead service lines for
working families while simultaneously
using decade old voter funds to perform
free environmental cleanup for heavy
industrial developers.
>> Point of order has been called and
taken. You were doing good and then you
got off track at the end. Thank you, Mr.
Miller. Any other comments from the
public
hearing? None. Do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> Uh Mr. Chairman, I move to approve an
amount not to exceed $314,950.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody,
seconded by Councilman Wolf. Comments
from the committee.
>> Real quick, Mr. Chairman.
>> Go ahead, Mr. Moody.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman, through you.
Um, just so the public is aware, this is
by Lowe's distribution center. Everybody
knows my opinion on data centers. This
has nothing to do with data centers.
Okay, it's me saying this. This is this
is something that's been needed to be
done and again it just happens over
time. So that's why be an I vote. Thank
you.
>> Thank you for that clarification. Any
other comments?
Hearing none. Do I have a motion on the
bid consideration? Please signify but
Oh, sorry. Oh, sorry.
I've been out of practice. It's been
moved and seconded. If there's no
further comments from the committee, all
those in favor of the big consideration,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed. There's no one nothing opposed.
That item will move forward. Next item.
Jen.
>> Number 12J. Consideration of bid number
S-12-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Northstar Concrete for the
2026 miscellaneous concrete project.
>> Staff report, please.
Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman and members
of the committee. Doug Clon, city
construction manager. Before you and for
your consideration today is the uh
consideration of the contract between
city of Cheyenne and Northstar concrete
for the 2026 miscellaneous concrete
project. This project specifically
targets um
intersection upgrades and primarily ADA
in those situations and it also
addresses some drainage concerns with
cross pans um when we when we go through
these projects. This particular project
will address approximately 13 locations
throughout our city. We did receive
seven bids for this project
uh with the apparent low bidder being
Northstar Concrete in the amount of
$500,175.50.
Staff has reviewed this process and
their bid and it is our recommendation
that we move forward with the contract.
>> Thank you, Mr. Klein. Any comments or
questions from the committee?
>> Mr. CJ,
>> I just want to clarify why uh Mr. Clown
is here. Uh the funding source on this,
it's the current 23 to 26 um 1% sales
tax fund
>> through you, Mr. Chairman. Yes, sir.
That is the correct funding.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Any other questions for Mr.
Klene?
Hearing none comments from the public
behind you.
>> Councilman Labbourne. Welcome.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um I'm curious
if uh Mr. Clone can tell me is this some
of this fund here in the numerous
projects that he mentioned is some of
this going to go to the Gardinia
uh crosswalk project there at uh the
point park
>> Mr. Cl
>> through you Mr. chairman. No, this will
not go to the Gardinia fund. This is uh
specifically called out in locations
that we've identified over the past
year. However, there is funding also
available for the Gardinia crosswalk
project and it is pricing out as an
independent concrete bid to some local
contractors who are providing pricing
for it. So, it will happen in addition
to this project.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you, Councilman Leborn.
Any further comments from the public?
Go ahead, Mr. Miller.
>> Can you hear me?
>> We can.
Um, excuse me.
Uh,
you know, I I really
uh am kind of curious about how you guys
are running your meeting here. Uh, this
is Charles Miller for the record. Uh,
Mr. Chairman, members of the finance
committee,
uh, Charles Miller for the permanent
administrative record. I'm testifying
today to place
um a notice of constructive notice of
viewpoint discrimination, retaliatory
censorship, and extreme fiduciary
contradiction on today's transcript
regarding item 12J. Um just let the
record show that my microphone's been
cut repeatedly. Um
now
this contract is funded by the optional
1% sales tax. The work consists of
miscellaneous contract sidewalk up or
concrete sidewalk upgrades, drive
approaches, and curb reconstructions.
Um, look at this. Look at the numbers.
This administration is prepared to
authorize over half a million dollars
for concrete and curbs. Yet, this same
administration claims it lacks the
municipal funds to address the massive
EPA lead service line crisis. Capping
city replacement
>> of order has been called and taken. Uh,
are you going to continue complaining
about how we're spending not spending
money on one thing but um but not
addressing whatever issues you may have
with this particular project?
>> Is isn't that what my three minutes is
allowing me to do is to discuss your
spending
>> on this project?
>> On this particular project, sir. Yes,
sir. Absolutely. you have problems with
us spending $500,000 on concrete and ADA
upgrades, by all means.
>> Well, um I'm I'm just wondering, you're
saying that uh I'm not allowed to to
discuss
anything except this item. I can't
compare your guys' uh spending elsewhere
is what you're saying
>> or lack of lack of spending. Not only
are they different projects, sir,
they're also different sources of
funding. So, uh I think that that's the
key point there.
>> Okay. All right. Well, thank you.
>> Thank you, sir. Any other comments from
the public?
>> Hearing none. Do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
in the amount not to exceed $500,17550.
Second.
>> It's been moved by Councilman uh Wolf,
seconded by Councilman Moody. Comments
or questions from the committee?
Hearing none. All those in favor of this
bid consideration, please signify by
saying I. I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That item moves
forward. Next item, please. Number 12K,
consideration of bid number S-14-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and Vance Brothers LLC for the
2026 surface seal project.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, Doug Clon, city
construction manager. Before you and for
your consideration today is the contract
between city of Cheyenne and Vans
Brothers LLC for the surface seal
project 2020 2020 2026
surface seal project in this case uh
consists of a slurry seal and is part of
the pavement management program that we
have been accelerating over the last
four to five years. Um
the addition of this contract and the
quantity that we will place this year
will put us um in excess of 120 center
line miles of city streets that we've
been able to put slurry surfacing on
over these past several years. So as
with most of these projects, it's an
important piece of our pavement
management program and therefore we
continue to push this. We did receive
three bids for this project with Vance
Vance Brothers being the low bid at
$2,35,7526.
Staff has reviewed their bid and is in
support of moving forward with this
contract.
>> Thank you, Mr. Clon, and best of luck. I
I know I can speak on all of council and
this committee when we see the great
progress that's been made on our um road
con road road construction and
maintenance over the last few years. So,
thank you. Questions for Mr. Clan from
the committee.
>> Uh, m Mr. Chairman,
>> go ahead with Councilman Wolf and then
Councilman Crave.
>> Briefly through you. Thank you. Um, Mr.
Quan, thank you. Thank you for all your
work on this. Um, who is Vance Brothers?
Do we have experience with them uh doing
city projects?
>> Do you, Mr. Chairman? Um, not in any
recent history have they done a city
project. However, they um they do lead
the way in this industry. They are an
important part of not only local um
western United States projects, but they
do take a leadership role in in surface
seal production and putting on training
and and attending and and um new
technology, those types of things. So
they they are a nationally renowned
company who specializes in this type of
work.
>> Councilman Crave.
>> Yes, sir. I just would like to confirm
the uh funding source. Once again, it
appears to be the 2023 through 20 26 1%
sales tax fund.
>> So you Mr. Chairman, that is correct. It
is is it is the newer fund.
>> Thank you. And that uh fund is a voter
approved for roads.
>> Yes.
>> Any other questions or comments from the
committee?
>> Hearing none. Comments from the public.
>> Go ahead, Mr. Miller.
Um, I'm going to go ahead and pass on
this one. Thank you.
>> Thank you, sir. Any other comments from
the public?
>> Hearing none, do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> M.
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
in in an amount not to exceed 2,35,7526.
>> Second.
Moved by Councilman Crra. Seconded by
Councilman Moody.
Questions or comments from the
committee?
>> Just real quick.
>> Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you. I just want to say I'm very happy
to Thank you, Mr. Quan. The one
neighborhood there off of uh Dell Range
North College and know they're very
happy to have that uh fully done. So,
thank you so much.
>> Any other comments or questions from the
committee hearing?
All those in favor of this big
consideration, please signify by saying
I. I.
>> It's been uh unanimously passed. No
one's opposed. That item moves forward.
Next item.
>> Number 12 L. Consideration of BIN number
S-15-26
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and ZNZ Seal Coding
Incorporated for the 2026 crack seal
project.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, Doug Clon, city
construction manager.
Before you and for your consideration is
a contract between the city of Cheyenne
and Z&Z seal coding for the 2026 crack
seal project. Again, this is an
important part of our payment management
program. In fact, this is the most
important part of our payment man
management program. It's not the
prettiest part, but this is the one that
makes all the difference.
Um when we are speaking about the
surfacing projects like we we just
approved uh this takes place typically a
year before that so that we ensure that
we're taking taking care of all the
moisture that may penetrate the asphalt
surfaces before we put a slurry seal on
them. This project goes further and that
it also takes care of major collectors
and arterials and making sure that we
those cracks up and prevent moisture
from entering that asphalt as well.
We did receive six bids for this project
uh with Z&Z seal coding being the low
bid at $443,23968.
Staff has reviewed the bids on this
project and we are in support of moving
the contract forward.
>> Thank you, Mr. Klein. Councilman Moody.
>> Yep. Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Through
you. Uh thank you, sir. Appreciate it.
Um, and again, I'm happy to see two uh
parts of the southern part here in Ward
3 uh being covered, especially by Cill
Drive and also Bon Nation Way too, those
neighborhoods there. So, thank you very
much. I know I've driven there recently.
Definitely need uh to be fixed. So,
thank you,
>> Councilman Crave.
>> Yes, sir. Once again, I just want to
confirm the funding source. It appears
to be the same uh 2023 through 2026 1%
sales tax.
Correct. Voter approved funding
specifically for road construction and
maintenance.
>> Thank you.
>> Any other questions or comments?
>> Hearing none comments from the public?
>> Hearing none. Do I have a uh any do I
have a motion from the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept an amount
not to receive $443,23968.
>> It's been moved by Councilman Moody. I'm
going to give the tie to Councilman
Crrave for the second. Any questions or
comments from the committee hearing?
None. All those in favor of this big
consideration, please signify by saying
I.
That's unanimous. No one's opposed. This
item will move forward. As there are no
other items on the agenda, this meeting
is adjourned. Thank you.